<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Pomodoro | Knowledge Is Everything]]></title>
  <link href="http://halyph.com/blog/categories/pomodoro/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://halyph.com/"/>
  <updated>2016-01-09T22:57:29+02:00</updated>
  <id>http://halyph.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Orest Ivasiv]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Review: The Pomodoro Technique by Francesco Cirillo]]></title>
    <link href="http://halyph.com/blog/2010/11/25/review-pomodoro-technique-by-francesco/"/>
    <updated>2010-11-25T01:48:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://halyph.com/blog/2010/11/25/review-pomodoro-technique-by-francesco</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Some time ago I read this book <a href="http://www.pomodorotechnique.com/products.html#pomodoropdf">&ldquo;The Pomodoro Technique&rdquo; by Francesco Cirillo</a><br /><span id="bxgy_x_title"><span class="bxgy-binding-byline"><span class="bxgy-byline-text">I have to say that it&rsquo;s really useful and super fast introduction for this particular time management technique. I highly recommend it for everybody interested in Pomodoro.</span></span></span><br /><span id="bxgy_x_title"><span class="bxgy-binding-byline"><span class="bxgy-byline-text">I don&rsquo;t want to analyze main chapters because you just have to read them all.</span></span></span><br /><span id="bxgy_x_title"><span class="bxgy-binding-byline"><span class="bxgy-byline-text">Of cause you read only about basic approaches and you have to adapt some of them. It&rsquo;s general practice. There is no single way to do the job, there is only recommended way to organize you work time. You have to start applying Pomodoro iteratively and make correction to &ldquo;your&rdquo; technique after each working day.</span></span></span><br /><br /><span id="bxgy_x_title"><span class="bxgy-binding-byline"><span class="bxgy-byline-text">Have fun with Pomodoro. </span></span></span></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Review: Pomodoro Technique Illustrated]]></title>
    <link href="http://halyph.com/blog/2010/09/11/review-pomodoro-technique-illustrated/"/>
    <updated>2010-09-11T18:34:00+03:00</updated>
    <id>http://halyph.com/blog/2010/09/11/review-pomodoro-technique-illustrated</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I&rsquo;ve got a real pressure because I had to learn TOO many different things simultaneous. And I had very small time frame to do the job in time. I needed some tool which can help me to organize all my learning activities.
<br />I remembered about Pomodoro. Without any delay I started reading this book: <a href="http://www.amazon.com/Pomodoro-Technique-Illustrated-Minutes-Pragmatic/dp/1934356506">Pomodoro Technique Illustrated: Can You Focus - Really Focus - for 25 Minutes?, by Staffan Noteber</a>
<br />
<br /><u>Chapter 1: One Activity at a Time</u>
<br />Pomodoro concepts overview. Author present simple examples which help us to understand the real value of this technique.
<br />
<br /><u>Chapter 2: Context</u>
<br />This chapter describes how our brain works. Basic ideas and simple worlds. It’s really pragmatic approach based on applicable examples and associations.
<br />
<br /><u>Chapter 3. Mechanics</u>
<br />This chapter help us to understand the Pomodoro process in action: Pomodoro sets, Activity, Iteration, breaks, Activity Inventory, Records.
<br />
<br /><u>Chapter 4. Interruptions</u>
<br />Clarifies the difference between the Internal and External interruption and gives several advices how to manage them.
<br />
<br /><u>Chapter 5. Estimate</u>
<br />Explains basic technique for Pomodoro estimation and estimate analysis.
<br />
<br /><u>Chapter 6. Adapt</u>
<br />This chapter shows some Pomodoro best practice: tools, length of Pomodoro, breaks, progress sheet, prioritizing, mind maps, reviews etc.
<br />
<br /><u>Chapter 7. Team</u>
<br />The last chapter, it gives some advices how to apply Pomodoro technique to pair work.
<br />
<br />In general this book opened my mind. I&rsquo;m going to try Pomodoro. The most beautiful thing it that this time management technique is very simple, has small set of rules and tools.
<br />
<br />Summary: well written book, short and pragmatic. Good start point to learn Pomodoro technique and adapt it to your own needs.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
