<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Octopress | Knowledge Is Everything]]></title>
  <link href="http://halyph.com/blog/categories/octopress/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://halyph.com/"/>
  <updated>2015-01-23T00:07:20+02:00</updated>
  <id>http://halyph.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Orest Ivasiv]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Migration to Octopress]]></title>
    <link href="http://halyph.com/blog/2014/09/07/migration-to-octopress/"/>
    <updated>2014-09-07T23:15:56+03:00</updated>
    <id>http://halyph.com/blog/2014/09/07/migration-to-octopress</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2>Objectives</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ve been blogging for several years (2009-2014) using Google Blogger <a href="http://halyph.blogspot.com">My old blogspot blog</a>. It was a great experience. But, I always felt some discomfort.
I couldn&rsquo;t simply write without thinking how it will be rendered. I was distracted by blog engine.</p>

<h2>Moving away</h2>

<p>Additional inspiration for moving away came from the essay <a href="http://tom.preston-werner.com/2008/11/17/blogging-like-a-hacker.html">Blogging Like a Hacker</a>.
Finally, I made a decision to use GitHub Pages for blogging. There were two choices: <a href="http://jekyllrb.com/">Jekyll</a> or <a href="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</a>.
I picked Octopress because of the pre-bundled minimal required blogging features. <em>I.e.</em> it&rsquo;s not required the additional configuration to start blogging right away.</p>

<p>The official Octopress <a href="http://octopress.org/docs/">documentation</a> has step-by-step guide for blog setup. It&rsquo;s very convenient and transparent.</p>

<h2>Theme</h2>

<p>I didn&rsquo;t want to use the default Octopress theme (it&rsquo;s boring). Theme customization required some time. All others free themes are too complex, IMHO.</p>

<p>At the end I found this <a href="http://blog.justin.kelly.org.au/octopress-theme/">theme</a> and applied it to my <em>new</em> blog.</p>

<h2>Main features</h2>

<p>Here I selected the main features which I like the most:</p>

<ul>
<li>markdown for blogging</li>
<li>simple code snippets insertion</li>
<li>full blog customization</li>
<li>Ruby at the bottom (I love this language)</li>
<li>ability to use your favorite text editor (Textmate in my case) for blogging</li>
</ul>


<h3>Minor Issues</h3>

<p>I&rsquo;ve tried to migrate posts form my old blog to Octopress, tried different approaches. But, I had no success. Actually, I had ugly results, which should be manually fixed.</p>

<h3>P.S.</h3>

<p>There are tons of different Static Site Generators, see the next resources:</p>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.staticgen.com/">Top Open-Source Static Site Generators</a></li>
<li><a href="http://staticsitegenerators.net/">Static Site Generators, The definitive listing of Static Site Generators — all 298 of them!</a></li>
</ul>


<p>But, Jekyll and Octopress are at the top.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
