<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Conference | Knowledge Is Everything]]></title>
  <link href="http://halyph.com/blog/categories/conference/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://halyph.com/"/>
  <updated>2015-06-29T23:54:23+03:00</updated>
  <id>http://halyph.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Orest Ivasiv]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[DevoxxPL - Krakow, 2015 - Report]]></title>
    <link href="http://halyph.com/blog/2015/06/29/devoxxpl/"/>
    <updated>2015-06-29T13:00:51+03:00</updated>
    <id>http://halyph.com/blog/2015/06/29/devoxxpl</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img class="right" src="/images/posts/2015-06/Devoxx-Poland-2015.png"></p>

<p>This summer I&rsquo;ve decided to attend my 1<sup>st</sup> foreign conference - <a href="http://devoxx.pl">DevoxxPL - Krakow, Poland, 22-25 June 2015</a>. It was very important experience, because I wanted to compare it with our local Ukrainian conferences. Long story short - the quality is equal. Any conference is based on speakers (I&rsquo;d like to be &ldquo;Captain Obvious&rdquo;). And even awesome conference location can&rsquo;t make conference <strong>great</strong>.</p>

<p>So, I&rsquo;ve attended the next talks:</p>

<a name="Day.1"></a>
<h2>Day 1</h2>

<ul>
<li><strong>&ldquo;The Silver Bullet Syndrome&rdquo;</strong> by <a href="http://hadihariri.com/">Hadi Hariri</a></li>
<li><strong>&ldquo;Tips and tricks for clean relational db schemas&rdquo;</strong> by <a href="https://twitter.com/clementd">Clément Delafargue</a></li>
<li><strong>&ldquo;JRebel under the covers - how is it even possible?&rdquo;</strong> by <a href="https://twitter.com/sjmaple">Simon Maple</a></li>
<li><strong>&ldquo;Corporate startup and Scala&rdquo;</strong> by <a href="https://plus.google.com/114974986229567009127/posts">Filip Rogaczewski</a> from <a href="spartez.com">Spartez</a>

<ul>
<li>It was really nice case study about building project with Scala. Pros&amp;cons were &ldquo;honestly&rdquo; highlighted.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>&ldquo;Refactoring to Functional&rdquo;</strong> by <a href="http://hadihariri.com/">Hadi Hariri</a></li>
<li><strong>&ldquo;You&rsquo;re an Architect&hellip;Now What?&rdquo;</strong> by <a href="https://twitter.com/ntschutta">Nathaniel Schutta</a></li>
</ul>


<a name="Day.2"></a>
<h2>Day 2</h2>

<ul>
<li><strong>&ldquo;Why software developers should care about deployment and monitoring&rdquo;</strong> by <a href="http://allegrotech.io/authors/michal.kosmulski/">Michał Kosmulski</a> from Allegro Group</li>
<li><strong>&ldquo;Modern Java Component Design with Spring 4.2&rdquo;</strong> by <a href="https://twitter.com/springjuergen">Juergen Hoeller</a> from Pivotal</li>
<li><strong>&ldquo;Make sense of your (BIG) data!&rdquo;</strong> by <a href="https://twitter.com/dadoonet">David Pilato</a> from ElasticSearch

<ul>
<li><a href="http://david.pilato.fr">Blog</a></li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>&ldquo;Building an Asynchronous Reactive NoSQL SDK with RxJava&rdquo;</strong> by <a href="https://about.me/simonbasle">Simon Baslé</a> from Couchbase</li>
<li><strong>&ldquo;Lazy Evaluations&rdquo;</strong> by <a href="https://twitter.com/venkat_s">Venkat Subramaniam</a>

<ul>
<li><a href="http://blog.agiledeveloper.com/2015/06/lazy-in-java_24.html">Blogpost - Lazy in Java</a></li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>&ldquo;Get Past the Syntax, The Real Scare is in the Semantics&rdquo;</strong> by <a href="https://twitter.com/venkat_s">Venkat Subramaniam</a></li>
</ul>


<a name="Day.3"></a>
<h2>Day 3</h2>

<ul>
<li><strong>&ldquo;PubSub++ - few tips that make your life with kafka easier&rdquo;</strong> by <a href="https://twitter.com/DebskiChris">Krzysztof Debski</a> from Allegro Group</li>
<li><strong>&ldquo;Deep dive into Reactive Java&rdquo;</strong> by <a href="https://twitter.com/tkowalcz">Tomasz Kowalczewski</a> from Codewise:

<ul>
<li><a href="http://www.slideshare.net/tkowalcz/deep-dive-reactive-java-devoxxpl">Slides</a></li>
<li><a href="https://github.com/tkowalcz/presentations">Github</a></li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>&ldquo;Event Sourcing &amp; Functional Programming - a pair made in heaven&rdquo;</strong> by <a href="https://twitter.com/rabbitonweb">Paweł Szulc</a>

<ul>
<li><a href="http://www.rabbitonweb.com/">Blog</a></li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>&ldquo;Functional Programming: Technical Reasons to Adapt&rdquo;</strong> by <a href="https://twitter.com/venkat_s">Venkat Subramaniam</a></li>
<li><strong>&ldquo;Why I love Logstash and you should too&rdquo;</strong> by <a href="https://twitter.com/jsvd">João Duarte</a> from ElasticSearch</li>
</ul>


<a name="Summary"></a>
<h2>Summary</h2>

<p>This conference had a huge buzz around microservices. I&rsquo;ve been inspired by some talks and planning to look deeper into:</p>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.elastic.co/products/elasticsearch">Elasticsearch</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.elastic.co/products/logstash">Logstash</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.elastic.co/products/kibana">Kibana</a></li>
<li><a href="https://github.com/ReactiveX/RxJava">RxJava</a></li>
<li>and OMG ;-) <a href="http://www.scala-lang.org/">Scala</a></li>
</ul>


<a name="References"></a>
<h2>References</h2>

<ul>
<li>Allegro

<ul>
<li><a href="http://allegrotech.io/open-source/">Open Source</a></li>
<li><a href="http://allegrotech.io/">Tech blog</a></li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><a href="https://www.elastic.co">Elastic</a>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.elastic.co/blog">Blog</a></li>
<li>Products:

<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.elastic.co/products/elasticsearch">Elasticsearch</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.elastic.co/products/logstash">Logstash</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.elastic.co/products/kibana">Kibana</a></li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><a href="http://babun.github.io/">Babun - a windows shell you will love</a></li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[JEEConf - Kiev, 2015 - Report]]></title>
    <link href="http://halyph.com/blog/2015/05/25/jeeconf-kiev/"/>
    <updated>2015-05-25T00:45:51+03:00</updated>
    <id>http://halyph.com/blog/2015/05/25/jeeconf-kiev</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img class="center" src="/images/blog/jeeconf.png"></p>

<p>It happened again - I attend <a href="http://jeeconf.com">JEEConf</a>, May 22-23, 2015. And as usual it was inspiring. Also, I can say that <a href="http://www.scala-lang.org/">&ldquo;Scala&rdquo;</a> was the most dominated buzz word at this conference.</p>

<p>So, I attended the next talks:</p>

<ul>
<li><p><strong>Pragmatic Functional Refactoring with Java 8, by Richard Warburton</strong> Java 8 functional features were introduced here. And were shown how we can refactor OOP program in functional way. I can say it&rsquo;s still a new way of thinking for Java developers.</p></li>
<li><p><strong>Just what are you doing, HotSpot? by Gleb Smirnov</strong> - Gleb gave us several advices for understanding tricky HotSpot behavior and why we should read HotSpot sources.</p></li>
<li><p><strong>Lessons from Implementing a Modern B2C System in Scala, by Yuriy Guts</strong> It was a case study talk about starting new project with Scala. The most interesting  was the issues appeared during project development, team&rsquo;s relationship with Scala, and Scala influences on non-Scala developers.</p></li>
<li><p><strong>Spring Puzzlers, by Evgeny Borisov and Baruch Sadogursky</strong> - We can say that this topic is unique. At least I&rsquo;m not aware of similar talks on other Java conferences. Spring Puzzlers is a variation of classic Java puzzlers, but in Spring. It&rsquo;s really great collection of tricky Spring parts.</p></li>
<li><p><strong>JVM Languages Q&amp;A Panel with Jacek Laskowski, Baruch Sadogursky, Dmytro Mantula, Alexander Podkhalyuzin, Tomer Gabel</strong> We can say that this panel was Groovy vs Scala. There are no other &ldquo;languages&rdquo; on this talk.</p></li>
<li><p><strong>Building an Enterprise-less online bank, Anton Keks</strong> - Anton doesn&rsquo;t love bloated Spring and likes simple and clean solution. He doesn&rsquo;t use Play Framework 2 on Scala because of slow compilation. Instead of this, he told us about his banking platform implemented on <em>Play 1.3</em> and <em>Java 8</em>, and all other items included in his stack.</p></li>
<li><p><strong>Everything you wanted to know about writing async, high-concurrency HTTP applications in Java, but were afraid to ask, by Baruch Sadogursky</strong> - Baruch shared his experience about implementing asynchronous file downloader in Java.</p></li>
<li><p><strong>Scala Rock-Painting, by Dmytro Mantula</strong> - This talk was like Scala puzzlers and/or Scala tricky parts. Speaker also gave us several suggesting how we can learn Scala more effectively via practicing <em>code katas</em> and/or <a href="http://ankisrs.net">Anki</a> flesh cards. This talk highlighted the &ldquo;dark&rdquo; side of Scala. Really, recommend it.</p></li>
<li><p><strong>Groovy under Macroscope, by Sergei Egorov and Baruch Sadogursky</strong> - Sergei demoed us very hacky Groovy library <a href="https://github.com/bsideup/MacroGroovy">MacroGroovy</a>. It&rsquo;s nice to see true Groovy hacker and his creature.</p></li>
<li><p><strong>About concurrency abstractions with Observable’s, Future’s, Akka (actors) in Scala, by Jacek Laskowski</strong> - Jacek did Scala concurrency overview talk and highlighted other non-Akka libraries. It&rsquo;s nice to know that there are other <em>&ldquo;good&rdquo;</em> way to do concurrency without Akka.</p></li>
<li><p><strong>Node.js and Evented I/O Alternatives on the JVM, by Niko Köbler</strong> - I definitely heard about <a href="https://avatar-js.java.net">Avatar.js</a>, but Niko told us that <a href="http://blog.n-k.de/2015/01/is-oracles-avatar-dead.html">Avatar.js is dead</a> and  <a href="http://blog.n-k.de/2015/02/current-status-of-oracles-project-avatar.html">Oracle put development of Avatar on hold</a>, i.e. full stop. As alternative were mentioned two solutions: <strong><a href="http://dynjs.org">DynJS</a></strong> an ECMAScript runtime for the JVM and <strong><a href="http://nodyn.io/">Nodyn</a></strong> - Node.js compatible framework on JVM. It&rsquo;s very interesting to see what will happen with them. <em>Nodyn</em> has strong RedHat support. Let&rsquo;s hope it&rsquo;s much stronger than Avatar.js had from  Oracle.</p></li>
<li><p><strong>Do we need JMS in 21st century? by Mikalai Alimenkou</strong> - The simple statements can be extracted from this talk: a) there are other non-JMS Message queues (MQs); b) we don&rsquo;t need bloated JMS for every tasks; c) use right MQ for right job</p></li>
</ul>


<a name="Summary"></a>
<h2>Summary</h2>

<ul>
<li><p>JEEConf has dedicated JVM track: 50% of this track was occupied by Scala (7 talks). As for me this is the sign ;-) Scala bandwagon reached Ukraine.</p></li>
<li><p><em>Microservices</em> everywhere. If you are not doing <em>microservices</em> - you should :-)</p></li>
</ul>


<p>Yes, JEEConf is simply the best. <a href="http://xpinjection.com/">XP Injection</a> did amazing work.</p>

<p><strong>Have fun, love Java!</strong></p>

<a name="References"></a>
<h2>References</h2>

<ul>
<li><a href="http://halyph.com/2014/05/jeeconf-kiev-2014-report.html">JEEConf - Kiev, 2014 - Report</a></li>
<li><a href="http://halyph.blogspot.com/2013/05/jeeconf-kiev-2013-report.html">JEEConf - Kiev, 2013 - Report</a></li>
<li><a href="http://halyph.blogspot.com/2012/05/this-year-we-had-second-jeeconf.html">JEEConf - Kiev, 2012 - Report</a></li>
<li><a href="http://halyph.blogspot.com/2011/05/jeeconf-kiev-2011-report.html">JEEConf - Kiev, 2011 - Report</a></li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[JEEConf - Kiev, 2014 - Report]]></title>
    <link href="http://halyph.com/2014/05/jeeconf-kiev-2014-report.html"/>
    <updated>2014-05-25T23:41:00+03:00</updated>
    <id>http://halyph.com/2014/05/jeeconf-kiev-2014-report</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img class="center" src="/images/blog/jeeconf.png"></p>

<p>I attended the forth <a href="http://jeeconf.com">JEEConf</a>, May 23-24, 2014. The situation in my country (Ukraine) is difficult that’s why I was amazed to see so many foreign speakers. The organizers did really tremendous work.</p>

<p>This year I divided topics by the next directions:</p>

<a name="Spring"></a>
<h3>Spring</h3>

<ul>
<li><em>Spring 4, Java EE 7 or Both? by Ivar Grimstad</em> &ndash; The main idea of the talk was to show similar and different parts of Spring 4 and Java EE 7. And have an ability easily identify when to use one or another. There are trade-offs and we should be aware of them.</li>
<li><em>Spring configuration: how to do it right (experience report), Mikalai Alimenkou</em> &ndash; Mikalai shared his experience related to Spring configs. Nice talk. I&rsquo;m going to borrow some ideas ;-)</li>
<li><em>Spring the Ripper, by Evgeny Borisov</em> &ndash; It was the most dynamic talk at this conference. The presenter shown Spring life-cycle internals in action. Well done. It should be seen by every Spring dev :-)</li>
</ul>


<a name="Frameworks"></a>
<h3>Frameworks</h3>

<ul>
<li><em>Apache Lucene/Solr Internals, by Anatoliy Sokolenko</em> &ndash; I had no experience with these technologies. And it was really nice intro. Now I have some clue how it works.</li>
<li><em>Streamline your processes with jBPM 6, by Jiri Svitak</em> &ndash; It was an into talk into jBPM 6. I had small experience with competitor framework <a href="http://activiti.org/">Activiti</a>. It&rsquo;s always interesting to see the similar framework&rsquo;s features.</li>
</ul>


<a name="Java.JVM.Compiler"></a>
<h3>Java/JVM/Compiler</h3>

<ul>
<li><em>Java8: Stream Style, by Sergey Kuksenko</em> &ndash; It was Java 8 Stream introduction. There were shown different stream features and approaches.</li>
<li><em><a href="http://shipilev.net/blog/2014/heapdump-is-a-lie/">What Heap Dumps Are Lying To You About, by Aleksey Shipilёv</a></em> &ndash; It&rsquo;s a very special talk related to Java &ldquo;internals&rdquo;. Actually, this talk was about Java object size calculation and what happens under the hood.</li>
<li><em>Reflection Madness, by Heinz Kabutz</em> &ndash; The presenter told us about Java reflection magic, when to use it and why it&rsquo;s dangerous.</li>
</ul>


<a name="Miscellaneous"></a>
<h3>Miscellaneous</h3>

<ul>
<li><em>Tooling of a Test-Driven Developer, by Paweł Lipiński</em> &ndash; There were highlighted two very interesting libraries for TDD on top of JUnit: <a href="http://joel-costigliola.github.io/assertj/">AssertJ</a> and <a href="https://code.google.com/p/junitparams/">JUnitParams</a>.Very interesting libraries</li>
<li><em>Web Apps in LISP!? EWW!, by Anatoly Polinsky</em> &ndash; Here was shown different aspects of web development in Clojure for beginners. It&rsquo;s was real intro, but very interesting, especially when you&rsquo;d like to spread your mind into alternative JVM-related communities.</li>
</ul>


<p>It was very productive conference for me. I&rsquo;ve got new portion of inspiration, new knowledge and passion to ordinary things.</p>

<p><img class="center" src="/images/posts/jeeconf2014.jpg"></p>

<a name="References"></a>
<h2>References</h2>

<ul>
<li><a href="http://halyph.blogspot.com/2013/05/jeeconf-kiev-2013-report.html">JEEConf - Kiev, 2013 - Report</a></li>
<li><a href="http://halyph.blogspot.com/2012/05/this-year-we-had-second-jeeconf.html">JEEConf - Kiev, 2012 - Report</a></li>
<li><a href="http://halyph.blogspot.com/2011/05/jeeconf-kiev-2011-report.html">JEEConf - Kiev, 2011 - Report</a></li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
