<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Evernote | Knowledge Is Everything]]></title>
  <link href="http://halyph.com/blog/categories/evernote/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://halyph.com/"/>
  <updated>2015-09-23T06:22:09+03:00</updated>
  <id>http://halyph.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Orest Ivasiv]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Long Way to Evernote]]></title>
    <link href="http://halyph.com/blog/2013/04/27/the-long-way-to-evernote/"/>
    <updated>2013-04-27T16:39:00+03:00</updated>
    <id>http://halyph.com/blog/2013/04/27/the-long-way-to-evernote</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><a href="http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-HINZJYkI8ZY/UTSsAlf6PYI/AAAAAAAABMo/ppAreJ9qJUE/s1600/8b5e386972fdb33153417b06e79ec99d-702602.jpeg" imageanchor="1" style="margin-left: 1em; margin-right: 1em;"><img border="0" src="http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-HINZJYkI8ZY/UTSsAlf6PYI/AAAAAAAABMo/ppAreJ9qJUE/s1600/8b5e386972fdb33153417b06e79ec99d-702602.jpeg" /></a></div>


<p><br />Have you ever think about the application (and/or service) which can satisfy all your &ldquo;productivity&rdquo; needs? The term &ldquo;productivity&rdquo; in this context is very simple - it&rsquo;s something (tools or methods) which helps you work with higher productivity, spent less time resolving boring tasks and concentrate on your business needs.<br /><br />Here I describe the areas which helps me be more productive and tools related with them.<br /><ol><li><b>Personal Knowledge Base (KB) System.</b> It&rsquo;s might be wiki, some notes taking application. I&rsquo;d been using <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Microsoft_OneNote" target="_blank">MS OneNote</a>. It&rsquo;s very powerful application with tons of nice features. Except it&rsquo;s supported on Microsoft OS&rsquo;s only. Also, I love using tons of tags for everything, but OneNote doesn&rsquo;t work well with tags.</li><li><b>Task Management System.</b> I&rsquo;ve been practicing the <a href="http://pomodorotechnique/" target="_blank">Pomodoro Technique</a>. And it&rsquo;s very hard to manage tons of tasks without some application. If you google a little you will find huge amount of applications and services which might be used for Pomodoro. I&rsquo;ve configured <a href="http://www.codeproject.com/Articles/5371/ToDoList-6-6-6-Feature-Release-An-effective-and-fl" target="_blank">TodoList </a>application to use it properly in scope of Pomodoro. It&rsquo;s was fun. But there was one drawback - I had one application for knowledge base and another for tasks management. It was a pain to link some tasks with article from my KB system.</li><li><b>Bookmarking</b>. I don&rsquo;t like to have super huge bookmark list inside my browser. I prefer to store the next thing in browser bookmarks: a) resources which I&rsquo;ve been visiting on daily/weekly basis and b) temporary links. All the bookmarks were stored on social bookmarking platform <a href="https://delicious.com/" target="_blank">delicious</a>. And again I had 3d tool which hard to integrate with others.</li></ol>OneNote and TodoList is Windows based application. But, I&rsquo;ve switched Mac and Android as my target home devices. My work machine is Windows based. So, I&rsquo;ve started research of analogues for KB and todo list applications which works quite well on Windows, Mac OS X and Android.<br /><br />As you probably guess it&rsquo;s <a href="https://evernote.com/" target="_blank">Evernote</a>. Here I highlight features which I love:<br /><ul><li>almost <b>cross-platform </b>(Windows, Mac OS X, iOS and Android), Linux isn&rsquo;t supported officially. But there is a work for Linux as well <a href="http://sourceforge.net/projects/nevernote/" target="_blank">NixNote</a> (old name NeverNote).</li><li>Evernote is a <b>service</b>. I.e. all my notes are synchronized between all my devices. Even more,&nbsp; Evernote has Web analogue of native note taking application. So, I can have access to my notes from anywhere.</li><li>Evernote has very power <b>tag</b> support. I can apply multiple tags my notes. It improves notes search and classification.</li><li>Knowledge Base, Pomodoro System and Bookmarks are all integrated into Evernote. I have single application for managing all these stuff. And it&rsquo;s real benefit, because my user experience is shared between all my devices and productivity concepts (KB, Pomodoro/Todo and Bookmarks).</li><li>Evernote has public Cloud API and Local API. I.e. we can automate Evernote experince.</li><li>There is very nice browser plugin <a href="http://evernote.com/webclipper/" target="_blank">Evernote Web Clipper</a> which store web pages (link, selected part of page or full page) into the notes. Very cool feature for bookmarking and KB.</li></ul><br />Evernote is very flexible application and a service. It was required some time for me to completely switch to Evernote from other application and services. But now I&rsquo;m more productive.<br /><br />If you have any question about my Evernote experience ask me. I will be glad to share it.<br /><br /></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Delicious. Evernote. Move Bookmarks. Security Issues.]]></title>
    <link href="http://halyph.com/blog/2013/03/04/delicious-evernote-move-bookmarks/"/>
    <updated>2013-03-04T16:23:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://halyph.com/blog/2013/03/04/delicious-evernote-move-bookmarks</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div style="text-align: center;"><img alt="" border="0" height="200" id="BLOGGER_PHOTO_ID_5851490941927046530" src="http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-HINZJYkI8ZY/UTSsAlf6PYI/AAAAAAAABMk/4kZWVw4ILo8/s200/8b5e386972fdb33153417b06e79ec99d-702602.jpeg" width="200" />&nbsp;</div>


<p>I&rsquo;ve been using&nbsp;<a href="http://delicious.com/">delicious.com</a> social bookmarking service several years. In my toolbox were Firefox add-on, Android app and their Web UI access.<br /><br /><div>But, last <b>Friday</b> I had strange issue. I couldn&rsquo;t create any bookmark and I couldn&rsquo;t view my &ldquo;delicious&rdquo; bookmarks via web UI.</div><div><br /></div><div>Then I&rsquo;ve tried to get all my bookmarks via <a href="https://delicious.com/developers">REST API</a>&nbsp;and I had a success</div><div><span style="font-family: &quot;Courier New&quot;,Courier,monospace;"><a href="https://USERNAME:PASSWORD@api.del.icio.us/v1/posts/all">https://USERNAME:PASSWORD@api.del.icio.us/v1/posts/all</a></span></div><div>At least I have a backup of all my bookmarks.</div><div><br /></div><div>As an&nbsp;<a href="https://evernote.com/">Evernote</a> user I&rsquo;ve decided to move/export/import all my&nbsp;Delicious bookmarks into Evernote. Very quick googling gave me this&nbsp;awesome solution:</div><div><a href="http://dr-palaniraja.blogspot.com/2010/12/import-delicious-bookmarks-to-evernote.html">Import Delicious bookmarks to Evernote including tags</a>. The author wrote small script (for Mac/Windows) which properly imports&nbsp;Delicious bookmarks into Evernote. Just check it out.</div><div>He&rsquo;s also provided sources in case you&rsquo;d like to improve/fix scripts:&nbsp;<a href="https://github.com/palaniraja/delicious2evernote"><a href="https://github.com/palaniraja/delicious2evernote">https://github.com/palaniraja/delicious2evernote</a></a>.</div><div><br /></div><div>Next day (last <b>Saturday</b>) I had been experiencing issues with Evernote also. Evernote resets my passwords and I had to re-type it. Very strange.</div><div><br /></div><div>It looks to me that I switched from one unstable service to another :-) . So, I&rsquo;ve decided to check twitter/blogs just to understand what going on. And, what a&nbsp;surprise:<br /><br /><b>Delicious </b></div><div><a href="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/--oWggPSoZ7c/UTSsBFs2ceI/AAAAAAAABMw/cUr6OM5zZqM/s1600/3ab909c669938b8f3eaed5e14aecfaf2-704271.png"><img alt="" border="0" height="145" id="BLOGGER_PHOTO_ID_5851490950571258338" src="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/--oWggPSoZ7c/UTSsBFs2ceI/AAAAAAAABMw/cUr6OM5zZqM/s400/3ab909c669938b8f3eaed5e14aecfaf2-704271.png" width="400" /></a></div><div><br /><b>Evernote</b></div><div><a href="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-JUoHwn844x8/UTSsBns3MeI/AAAAAAAABM8/sBH1wFYWJJk/s1600/3f46ed9575f20466fc69e13fc3c43e9e-706897.png"><img alt="" border="0" height="72" id="BLOGGER_PHOTO_ID_5851490959698112994" src="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-JUoHwn844x8/UTSsBns3MeI/AAAAAAAABM8/sBH1wFYWJJk/s400/3f46ed9575f20466fc69e13fc3c43e9e-706897.png" width="400" /></a></div><div><blockquote class="tr_bq">Evernote’s Operations &amp; Security team has discovered and blocked suspicious activity on the Evernote network that appears to have been a coordinated attempt to access secure areas of the Evernote Service.  As a precaution to protect your data, we have decided to implement a password reset. Please read below for details and instructions.</blockquote><br /></div><div>In any case I&rsquo;ve migrated all my bookmarks to Evernote. I&rsquo;m going to use Evernote as centralize knowledge&nbsp;system: wiki, bookmarking, todo.</div></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
